Preliminary Inventory to the John Hiestand Collection, 1942-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
John Hiestand Collection,
1942-1945
72043
Hiestand, John, collector
1 manuscript box, 2 scrapbooks. (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Letters, conference proceedings, transcripts of radio broadcasts, propaganda leaflets, and printed matter, relating primarily to the work of the United States Office of War Information and the United States Army Psychological Warfare Branch in the Southwest Pacific, 1944-1945.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. Psychological Warfare Branch.; United States. Office of War Information.; Propaganda, American.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; World War, 1939-1945--Psychological aspects.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.
Container List
- Letter of appreciation from Brigadier General Bonner F. Fellers to Elmer Davis, Director of the Office of War Information (OWI), November 1, 1944 (Box 1)
- Letter from Earl M. Thacker to friends, relating his account of military rule in Hawaii Nei, April 7, 1942
- Proceedings of the Conference of OWI Chiefs of Outposts in the Pacific Area, May 24-27, 1945, Monterey, California
- Transcripts of broadcasts of "The Philippine Hour," an OWI radio program in the Philipplines, October 1944 - May 1945
- OWI pamphlets
- Special editions of the Free Philippines, August 14 and September 3, 1945
- Printed matter
- Souvenirs: pencil, " `I shall return' --MacArthur"; match box, "I shall return"
- Oversize Scrapbook of propaganda leaflets released in the Southwest Pacific by the Psychological Warfare Branch, U.S. Army, Pacific Area (Volume 1 volume)
- "Manchoukuo, An Epic," a picture book, n.p., n.d. (Volume 1 volume)